For this question, there are a couple of different things you're going to need to do.
对于这道题目 你需要完成好几个任务
You're given inputs which are a string, a pattern number and generations--
这些是输入 包括字符串 pattern 数字和 generations
the number of times you're going to apply the pattern to the string.
即将 pattern 应用到字符串的次数
The first thing we're going to need to do is to take the pattern number and convert it
首先我们需要传入 pattern 数字
into some sort of pattern that we're going to be able to use to apply to our string.
并转换为某种能够应用到字符串的 pattern
The second thing we're going to need to do is create a new string by applying
其次 我们需要通过将该 pattern 应用到字符串上创建新的字符串
the pattern to string, and we're going to do that generation times.
并重复 generations 次
Finally, we're going to need to return the last new string that we create.
最后 我们需要返回创建的最后一个新字符串
Let's first look at how we can create the pattern from the pattern number.
先看看如何通过 pattern 数字创建 pattern
We're given a number of each of the patterns,
对于每个 pattern 都给出了一个数字
and one thing I noticed about these are they are actually the powers of 2.
注意到的一点是它们是 2 的幂次方
I'm going use that in my code. You don't have to. You can use the numbers as they are there.
我将在代码中用到这一点 你不需要 可以直接使用这些数字
But I decided to use them as powers of 2.
但是我决定使用 2 的幂次方
Now, if you're given a pattern number, you need to find out whether 128 goes into that pattern number.
如果给定 pattern 数字 你需要查看 128 是否满足这一 pattern
I'm going to do integer division by 2^7.
我将除以整数 2^7
If that's 1, I'm going to know that X X X corresponds to X in my new string.
如果是 1 则知道在新字符串中 X X X 对应的是 X
That's my rule.
这是我的规则
I decided to make a dictionary.
我决定创建一个字典
X X X is going to be my key and X is my value.
XXX 是键 X 是值
If it's 0 then X X X, then X X X would correspond to a dot.
如果是 0 那么 XXX 对应一个点
Once I've done that, I need to see what the remainder is.
完毕后 我需要知道余数是多少
What the rest of the number is after I've subtracted 128 from it--if it was 1 or nothing.
除以 128 后剩下的数字是多少 如果是 1 或 0
I can use modulo for that.
我可以使用模数
This is going to be my new pattern number.
这将是新的 pattern 数字
On my new pattern number, I'm now going to divide by 2^6.
现在将对新的 pattern 数字除以 2^6
Again, if it's 1, I'm going to make the corresponding pattern a key with value X.
同样 如果是 1 则键对应值 X
If it's 0, I'm going to make the corresponding value dot.
如果是 0 则对应值点
I'm going to continue running through all the values here--all the numbers here--
我将继续查看所有这些值 所有这些数字
down to the bottom, seeing which ones correspond to an X
看看哪些对应 X
and which correspond to a dot.
哪些对应点
The way I'm going to do it is to use these numbers here
我将使用这些数字
and run through those backwards.
往回检查
Onto the code.
现在看看代码
I said that I was going to set up a dictionary of my patterns.
我提到了我要创建 pattern 字典
I'll initialize patterns to be the empty dictionary.
我将 pattern 初始化为空字典
I'm going to write all the patterns so that I can refer to them.
将所有 pattern 写成列表 以便引用它们
For convenience, I'm just going to let n equal the length of the string,
为了简便 我将 n 设为等于字符串长度
because I'm going to use it several times.
因为我将多次用到它
I've got two things to do.
现在有两个任务要完成
I've got to build my patterns dictionary, and I've got to make a new string
我需要构建 pattern 字典 并且通过向字符串中应用 pattern
by applying pattern to string.
创建新的字符串
I'm going to do that generations times.
并重复 generations 次
First, let me build the patterns dictionary.
首先构建 pattern 字典
As I said, I'm going to loop through the numbers 7 down to 0 in reverse order.
正如之前提到的 我将按照递减顺序从 7 循环到 0
Do exactly as I said before, check whether pattern number is divisible by 2 to the power of that number.
和之前的操作完全一样 检查 pattern 数字是否能被该数字的 2 次幂整除
If that's equal to 1--strictly speaking, I don't need to actually say ==1,
如果等于 1 严格说来 不需要写成 ==1
because 1 counts as true.
因为 1 等同于 True
But just for readability I'm going to put it in.
但为了可读性 我还是写上
If it's equal to 1, then I'm going to subtract power from the pattern number.
如果等于 1 那么将 pattern 数字减去该幂
If it's equal to 0, then the corresponding value is dot instead of x.
如果等于 0 那么对应的值是点 而不是 X
That completes the dictionary, and now we go on to the loop,
字典创建完毕 现在开始编写循环部分
which is going to run generations times to change the string into a new string.
将运行 generations 次以将字符串变成新的字符串
For j in the range of 0 up to generations, I'm going to make a new string,
for j in range(0, generations) 创建一个新字符串
which is the empty string.
是个空字符串
I'm going to loop through the old string or through the indexes in the old string.
循环浏览旧字符串 即旧字符串中的索引
What we're going to do now is step through the string, looking at every pattern.
现在要做的是浏览该字符串 查看每个 pattern
So we need to build up our pattern.
我们需要构建 pattern
What is a pattern?
什么是 pattern？
It's the central character that we're looking at,
也就是我们要查看的中心字符
and it's the neighbor the left and the neighbor to the right.
以及左右两侧的字符
Just let's think about that for a moment.
先思考下
Does this cause any problems at the end of the strings?
这会导致字符串出现任何问题吗？
Because if i is 0, we're right at the beginning of the string.
如果 i 为 0 则写到字符串的开头
What happens to i - 1? Well, we get -1.
i - 1 会怎样？得出 -1
Because Python allows us to index from the reverse of a string, that's fine.
因为 Python 允许我们从后往前对字符串编制索引 所以没关系
That will be the last element of a string followed by the first one,
这将是字符串的最后一个元素 跟着第一个字符
followed by the second one, which is just what we want.
然后是第二个字符 正是我们需要的
Let's check the other end of the string.
我们看看字符串的另一端
If i is the last element of the string, then we've got a problem.
如果 i 是字符串的最后一个元素 那么就有问题了
This element here is after the end of the string,
该元素在字符串末尾之后
so we're going to get an error. What do we want it to be?
所以我们就会遇到错误 我们希望它成为什么？
We want it to be the first element of the string.
我们希望它成为字符串的第一个元素
And in order to do that, I'm going to use modulo n,
为此 我将使用模数 n
because i + 1 when we're at the end of the string i is n - 1.
因为 i + 1 当我们位于字符串末尾时 i 是 n - 1
Plus 1 gives me n, and n modulo n is 0--the first element of the string, which is what we want.
+1 得出 n n%n 是 0 即字符串的第一个元素 正是我们想要的
There we have our pattern.
pattern 就写好了
We need to look up our pattern in the dictionary,
我们需要在字典中查询我们的 pattern
and we need to add whatever the character is that our central character changes to--
我们需要将中心字符变成的字符
that i changes to--to our string.
i 变成的字符添加到 new_string
Looking it up in patterns, I'll get that character.
在 patterns 中查找得出该字符
Once it's run through the whole length of the string,
浏览完整个长度的字符串后
then I make my string equal to the new string and the loop continues.
让我的字符串等于 new_string 继续循环
Once that's done generations number of times, I return the new string.
循环 generations 次后 返回 new_string
That completes the procedure apart from a couple of typos.
这一过程就完成了 当然还有一些错别字
That should say for i in range, and I managed to change my variable name here.
应该写成 for i in range 这里的变量名称也需要修改下
It should say pattern instead of patterns.
应该是 pattern 而不是 patterns